<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Orestes Carracedo</title>
    <link href="http://blog.orestes.io/atom.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="http://blog.orestes.io" />
    <updated>2013-06-26T21:08:51+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.orestes.io</id>
    <author>
        <name></name>
        <email>orestes.ca@gmail.com</email>
    </author>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Migrating from Wordpress to Jekyll on GitHub Pages</title>
        <link href="http://blog.orestes.io/archive/2013/06/09/migrating-from-wordpress-jekyll-github-pages"/>
        <updated>2013-06-09T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
        <id>http://blog.orestes.io/archive/2013/06/09/migrating-from-wordpress-jekyll-github-pages</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Besides my writting skills, my problem with blogging was the software I was using, Wordpress. Although I made use of lots of the features something just never seemed right. I found it slow heavy and often insecure. I didn&amp;#8217;t want my vm exploding whenever I got a traffic spike, I didn&amp;#8217;t want to be patching and upgrading my WP modules and being worried about security issues. It was kind of hard to get it to look the way I wanted it. I wrote a custom theme but I wasn&amp;#8217;t really satisfied with it, so I bought a one which looked cool, but I still wasn&amp;#8217;t happy with my blog because it wasn&amp;#8217;t &amp;#8220;mine&amp;#8221;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted a static blog website that I could code and style however I wanted. So I started researching about scaffolding tools and generators for static websites and I found about GitHub Pages and Jekyll. I had read about them in the past but never really tried. When I got to it I knew I had found the solution for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pros of switching from WP on my hosting to Jekyll on gh-pages&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t have to worry about security issues since everything is static&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I can version my posts and contents using a CVS I love (git)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I can &lt;em&gt;easily&lt;/em&gt; share the source code for my blog&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t have to worry about hosting&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I can use any domain I own&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;It provides higher geek factor than having a WP blog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cons&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GitHub crashes every once in a while and maybe GH Pages come down with it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the next few days I&amp;#8217;ll try to add the old posts and extend them a bit. I also have a bunch of drafts that I never got around to publish so I&amp;#8217;ll try to finish them too.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Ilya Grigorik; Breaking the 1000ms Time to Glass Mobile Barrier</title>
        <link href="http://blog.orestes.io/archive/2013/04/10/breaking-the-1000ms-time-to-glass-mobile-barrier"/>
        <updated>2013-04-10T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
        <id>http://blog.orestes.io/archive/2013/04/10/breaking-the-1000ms-time-to-glass-mobile-barrier</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/Il4swGfTOSM?feature=oembed&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Il4swGfTOSM&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the slides from the talk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can read more about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.appliness.com/ilya-grigorik/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ilya on his interview featured on Applines&lt;/a&gt; a few months ago.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Creepy streaming</title>
        <link href="http://blog.orestes.io/archive/2012/07/05/creepy-streaming"/>
        <updated>2012-07-05T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
        <id>http://blog.orestes.io/archive/2012/07/05/creepy-streaming</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;img class=&quot;pic&quot; src=&quot;http://blog.orestes.io/media/2012/07/05/endesa-450x272.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;endesa&quot; width=&quot;450&quot; height=&quot;272&quot; /&gt;
&lt;label&gt;Taking a peek at a player streaming video using low settings looks creepy&lt;/label&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Having lunch at Toyo</title>
        <link href="http://blog.orestes.io/archive/2012/04/26/having-lunch-at-toyo"/>
        <updated>2012-04-26T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
        <id>http://blog.orestes.io/archive/2012/04/26/having-lunch-at-toyo</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;img src=&quot;http://blog.orestes.io/media/2012-04-26-01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Having lunch at Toyo&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really love this restaurant. It has a classic sushi conveyor belt and is just one block away from the office.
The owners are actually chinese but their food is amazing! They're so nice and they've even learned our preferences so
whenever I sit down I get the first Teriyaki Chicken that comes out of the kitchen. We have lunch here almost every week
and they make us feel really welcomed. I'm going to miss this place when we move to the new office, wherever that may be...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're ever in Barcelona, check out &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.restaurantetoyo.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Toyo&lt;/a&gt;, you'll love it'&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    </entry>
    
</feed>
