<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

    <title>Orestes Carracedo</title>
    <link href="http://blog.orestes.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
    <link href="http://blog.orestes.io"/>
    <updated>2013-06-09T21:34:14+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.orestes.io</id>
    <author>
        <name>Orestes Carracedo</name>
        <email>orestes.ca@gmail.com</email>
    </author>

    
    <entry>
        <title>Migrating from Wordpress to Jekyll on GitHub Pages</title>
        <link href="http://blog.orestes.io/2013/06/09/migrating-from-wordpress-jekyll-github-pages.html"/>
        <updated>2013-06-09T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
        <id>http://blog.orestes.io/2013/06/09/migrating-from-wordpress-jekyll-github-pages</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My blogging has been irregular, erratic and inconsistent since I started in 2011, and I&amp;#8217;m trying to improve. I read a lot of interesting blogs and I follow a lot interesting developers, so I&amp;#8217;m constantly thinking about all this new ideas and discussions, and they really make an impact on me. This results in a lot of experiments that I&amp;#8217;ve been collecting on my lab, which I&amp;#8217;m also organising and trying to order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides my writting skills, my problem was my blogging software, Wordpress. I think it&amp;#8217;s just too much for what I want. I don&amp;#8217;t need something dynamic, slow (even if I use caching systems), heavy and potentially insecure. I don&amp;#8217;t want my vm exploding whenever I get a traffic spike, I don&amp;#8217;t want to be patching and upgrading my WP modules and being worried about security issues. I want a static blog website, and the awesome &lt;a href='http://disqus.com'&gt;Disqus&lt;/a&gt; for the comments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I started researching about scaffolding tools and generators for static websites and I found about GitHub Pages and Jekyll. I had read about them in the past but never really tried them, and I must say they&amp;#8217;re a perfect fit. I can use any domain I own, I can share the source code for my blog, I can version my posts and contents and I don&amp;#8217;t have to worry about security updates or server resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been getting busy with &lt;a href='http://jekyllrb.com'&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href='http://pages.github.com'&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt; for the past week and I must say I love it.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    </entry>
    

</feed>